[Music]
Good evening everyone. Good evening. Um,
you all go ahead and
let me know if you could hear me
and if you can see me.
Let's put a one in that chat.
Welcome everybody. Welcome, welcome,
welcome.
All right. Can you all hear me?
Okay. So, you can see me and you can
hear me. All right. I just need to do
something. Um,
volume is low.
There we go. There we go.
All right. All right. Good evening,
everybody. I hope everyone is doing
well. Um, I hope you are excited about
tonight because tonight is going to be a
very special message. Uh, okay. My team
is working on the on the volume. So,
uh, hopefully you guys can hear me well.
Um,
all right. Very good. Very good. Very
good. Okay. Uh so guys, let's uh let's
let's have a word of prayer before we do
anything because tonight's message uh
tonight's study is going to be
absolutely
important and really challenging for
everybody.
Um,
whether you're a critic of Adventism,
whether you are one who has left
Adventism and decided you want to join
in and see what I have to say tonight.
Um, or if you're an Adventist,
uh, this message uh is it's going to
challenge you. It's going to challenge
you. So, uh, we need to pray. Now, um, I
see some of you saying that my volume is
low and I've got my mic uh right in
front of me. Some of you are saying it's
fine. Um, so I'm gonna I'm gonna kind of
leave that to leave that to my team to
work out. But hopefully you guys can
hear me well because I'm really talking
into the mic now. Um, all right you
guys, let's pray and let's get ready for
the study tonight. By the way, hit that
share button. Let people know that that
we are live right now. Tell them to tune
in because they don't want to miss this.
All right. Um, okay. Let's pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, we ask that uh as
we get into this study tonight that you
would bless us, Lord, that you would
open our eyes and our hearts. Lord, help
us
to understand how your spirit functions.
And Lord, most of all, uh, help our
hearts to be right with you
so that the promise can be fulfilled
that if we seek after you with all our
hearts, we will find you. And so we
thank you, Lord, for hearing. Lord,
bless your word now. Bless this study
now. We pray in Jesus name. And I want
to pray Lord for all who are watching
and who will watch.
Lord that they will understand the
nature of this challenge.
Please Lord reveal your mighty power is
our prayer in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Okay.
So, um,
we're going to, uh, we're going to go to
the screen
and, um, I will make my slides
available, by the way. I'll make my
slides available as I always do. Uh, but
tonight, as I said, is going to be a
very serious study. In fact, um, this
this study tonight,
um, entitled Ellen White and her
hypocritics. Yeah, that's a play on
words. Um, and you will see why I titled
it Ellen White. Ellen White and her
YouTube
hippo critics.
Ellen White and her YouTube hippo
critics.
I want to issue tonight the challenge,
which I'm calling the KTS
challenge. Now, I I think some of you
may have seen
um that KTSE and were wondering what is
KTSSE. And I'm not going to tell you
now. Um I will make it known a little
bit later on in the study, but you will
understand. And in fact, I'm going to
ask you uh uh every now and every now
and then I'm going to ask you to put
that KTS in the chat because you will
know what it means. And once you know
what it means, man, it's going to make a
world of difference in how you approach
um the critics who challenge you,
particularly when it comes to Ellen
White. So tonight's tonight's study is
in fact a warning to the critics
regarding the methods they use to try to
disprove Adventism and specifically the
methods they use to try to disprove
Adventism. our seventh um disprove
excuse me disprove Ellen White. Um
so uh with that said um let's I want to
talk to you tonight about five energies.
Five energies. Let's go to the screen uh
and you'll see here the hypocritic
arguments. And there are five energies
we are going to be looking at tonight.
five uh you know, five attitudes, five
arguments that I'm simply calling
energies. Um because these are kind of
what the the the critics they base their
argument off of and it empowers them.
They feel that this empowers them. Uh so
uh we're going to begin with energy
number one, anti-plagiarism.
anti-plagiarism.
The anti-plagiarism
enemy.
Um, I see some stuff in the chat that
I'm just not going to respond to because
um, honestly, I don't want y'all to
steal my thunder right now. So, I'm just
going to ignore some of the things I've
just seen. Anti-plagiarism
energy.
So, the anti-plagiarism energy of the
skeptics is this. Ellen White copied
from sources and therefore she is not
divinely inspired. So the argument is
and go ahead and put a one in the chat
if you have seen that argument. Um you
know Ellen White has copied and
plagiarized and it's one of the things
that a lot of these YouTube critics will
throw out there in hopes that you will
come to the conclusion that Ellen White
is a false prophet. she's a false
prophet because um there is evidence
that she copied from others and in in
their minds that proves that that Ellen
White is a false prophet. And so you'll
even see sometimes diagrams like you
know from
the book Desire of Ages will will be a
typical example and you'll see something
like you know uh a a half of a sentence
or maybe a sentence or maybe even you
know part of a paragraph that that may
be identical to something else that
someone wrote earlier.
So, uh, that is that is the anti-
plagiarism energy. And I'm now going to
introduce to you what KTS stands for.
We're going to go to the screen. We're
going to go to the screen and we're
going to see that KTS
stands for y'all put it in the chat for
me, please. Keep that same energy.
Let me see you put it in the chat on the
Bible. We just want to make sure that we
are all on the same page. Keep that same
energy.
Are we good? Y'all got it? I'm looking
for it in the chat. Keep that same
energy.
So, so what happens then when when the
critics
keep that same energy? something very
dangerous happens. And what I'm going to
suggest to you, beloved, is that the
energy that they use to condemn uh Ellen
White is a very dangerous energy. It's a
very dangerous energy. It's a very
dangerous method. Why? Why? Let's let's
focus for a moment on what it means to
keep that same energy. So a lot of
people when you hear them say you know I
left Adventism because I began studying
and seeing you know these things in
Ellen White and you know I began to
realize you know upon earnest study that
that she copied from other sources.
So here's the problem with that you
guys. Here's the problem with that.
Let's go to the screen and I'm just
going to read for a little while. Okay
let's go to the screen.
Um these are quotes from different
sources. Um, a lot of these are are
sources from atheists. So, let's read.
Many critical scholars in Western
universities suggest that the biblical
creation and flood stories borrowed
ideas from ancient neareastern texts.
For example, the creation story in
Genesis must be influenced in the
Babylonian creation story of Enuma Elish
since the story in Genesis is briefer
and the preserved records of Genesis
belong to a later date.
Both accounts share similar motifs of
pre primeval waters and the separation
of elements in creation suggesting
possible literary influence or shared
cultural understandings of origins.
Y'all put KTS in the chat for me. Please
keep that same energy. Let's keep
reading. Let's keep reading. We got a
lot to cover here. Um, I just pulled
this from one web page, at the Atlanta
Black Star. And here is the article,
eight biblical concepts and stories that
originated outside of the Bible. And
then it goes on to list those eight. And
we're not going to look at all eight,
but I just I'm just showing you some
examples. Okay? Keep that same energy.
That's what I'm saying to the critic
right now. Keep that same energy.
Pastor, what do you mean keep that same
energy? Let's keep moving on. So here
are
here are some of the biblical stories.
There's a lot of evidence that the epic
of Gilgamesh, one of the oldest recorded
texts in human history estimated to go
as far back as 22 B 2200 BC had an
influence on the biblical creation
story. The Epic of Gilgamesh tells a
story of a man in in Kindu who was
created by the from the earth by God. He
lives among the animals in a natural
paradise until he is tempted by a woman.
Let's keep reading. We're going to go to
the next page
and
says uh he cites several examples but
one was a quote from Sir Godfrey Higgins
the English orientalist as follows. He
says, "Another stride uh striding
instance is recorded by the very
intelligent traveler Wilson regarding a
representation of the fall of our first
parents sculptured in the magnificent
temple of the Ipsambbul in Nubia. He
says that a very exact representation of
Adam and Eve in the garden of Eden is
seen to be in that cave and that the
serpent climbing around the tree is
especially deline delineated and the
whole subject of the temptation of the
tempting of our first parents most
accurately exhibited
in the epic of Gilgamesh in Kendu was
tempted by a woman named Shamat. He
accepts food from this woman and is
forced to leave his paradise in the
forest after becoming aware of his own
nakedness. Later in the epic, he
encounters a snake which steals a plant
of immortality from him. He dies
forgetting the day when he turned into a
human.
Let's keep reading. Now,
for many of you, this may be a
challenge, but I just need you to follow
along because I'm trying to demonstrate
something to you here. So here's a chart
that shows similarities and some of the
differences between the Bible and the
Gilgamesh version. So remember how you
know the critics will take Ellen White
and they'll say see uh Ellen White
copied this story from here and so she
is a false prophet. Remember the
remember the premise and here you can
see in this chart uh that in the Genesis
story and the Gilgamesh story there are
things like the glove be the the flood
being global uh the cause man's
wickedness uh intended for whom all
mankind um sender Yahweh the sender
assembly of gods uh the na the name of
the hero is Noah the name of the hero in
the Gilgamesh story is napfishim
uh hero's character is righteous same
and Gilgamish. And it goes on. We're not
going to read through all of them. Just
just kind of laying something out here
for you. Okay. Here's more examples of
the parallels between these two stories.
Now, I want to I want let me just let me
just keep reading. I'm going to keep my
comments until the the end of this
particular section. So, let's keep
reading. Let's keep going.
Um Pandora's box. In Greek mythology,
Pandora was the first woman on Earth.
The god Zeus gave her a box and told her
not to open it. In the original Greek,
the object was a jar, but the two words
are similar. And it seems that Arasmus
or Arasmus mis mistransated it as box.
And that is what stuck. Inside the box
were all the troubles of the world,
including death. And when Pandora opened
it, the troubles escaped to plague the
whole world. Zeus had given her the box,
hoping that she would open it, thus
releasing trouble in the world. This was
his way of bringing trouble upon the
world since Promeththeus had given fire
to mankind. Let's keep reading. The
story of Pandora's box is an attempt to
explain why there is trouble in the
world. It does contain some aspects that
are similar to the account of Genesis 3
where God tells us how sin and death
entered the world. Now, I want you to
remember that in a lot of these
instances, what I'm going what I'm going
to be reading to you are either liberal
scholars or
critics of the Bible
who say
that the Bible cannot be trusted
because they have evidence that the
stories in the Bible were plagiarized.
Now y'all put a one in the chat if you
understand the significance
of keep that same energy.
Put a one in the chat if you are
catching the significance
of what I mean when I say keep that same
energy.
I'm not going to say it yet. I just want
to see if y'all are follow following
along.
All right, let's keep going. Let's keep
going.
Um, Noah's flood,
Genesis versus the Gilgamesh epic. It is
commonly accepted that parts of Genesis
1-11 show literary dependence either
directly or indirectly on Mesopotamian
literary tradition. The flood story in
Genesis 6-9 provides the best parallel
of these or the best examples of these
parallels. And there's a source, God in
translation, deities across cross
deities and cross-cultural discourse in
the biblical world. Let's keep going.
Let's keep going. Here's a paper called
Genesis and Gilgamesh. Parallels between
the Garden of Eden and the sacred cedar
forest by Adam Mig Miglo Miglio. What do
the book What do the book of Genesis and
the Epic of Gilgamesh have in common?
Surprisingly, a lot. Chapters 1- 11 of
Genesis reached their final form during
the 8th uh 8th to fifth century BC when
the people of Judah were in were in
sustained contact with Mesopotamian
polities. And for this reason, Genesis
1-11 shares the epic of Gilgamesh
stories of wy serpents, demagogues, a
catastrophic flood, supernatural plants,
and herculean feats of engineering. So,
let me ask you a question. Let me ask
you a question. Now, listen. The purpose
of this tonight is not for you to say,
"No, no, no, pastor, that's wrong, and
this is why." I know
I I don't believe
that what the critics are saying about
the Bible that, "Oh, they borrowed and
this is just plagiarism." I don't
believe that. So, the argument for me
right now is not, "Oh, but pastor,
that's wrong." I get it's wrong. I know
it's wrong. I just want you to see what
the critics of the Bible say. The
critics of the Bible use the exact same
method against the Bible that critics of
Adventism will use against Ellen White.
And those same critics, when faced with
these uh uh uh uh uh evidences of the
Bible being plagiarized, will go out on
a limb to explain why it's not
plagiarism. Are y'all with me? Do you
see an inconsistency
in the energy?
These very same critics
who will say, "Oh, look at Ellen White.
Look, she plagiarized this, she
plagiarized that. Look, you can s look
at this here and look at that there.
Look at the copy of the sentence. They
will ignore the atheist who also says,
"Look at the Bible. The Bible copied
from this and this." These stories are
just myths that were borrowed from other
cultures. Come on, y'all. Let's keep
going. Put in the chat, if you want to
say an amen, don't say amen. Just put
KTSC in the chat. Just put KTS in in the
chat. Keep that same energy. Let's keep
reading. Uh here's another book, the
religion, the greatest confidence trick
in history. The following stories are
far older than the pentatuk
and contain much the same elements. In
the Persian story, God created the world
in six days. A man called Adam and a
woman called Eva and then rested. The
estrusian, Babylonian, Phoenician,
Calaldian, and Egyptian stories are much
the same. The Persians, Greeks, and
Egyptians had their garden of Eden and a
tree of life. And it goes on, I want you
to see that in a critic's mind, it is
absolutely obvious that the Bible
was plagiarized.
In the atheist mind, it is how how can
that cult call Christianity and that's
what they call Christianity, is it not?
Do they not call it a cult? Do they not
say, "Can't they see that the Bible is
plagiarized?" And yet these same
Adventist critics will take that spirit,
that energy, and apply it to Ellen
White, but are not consistent when it
comes to the Bible. In other words,
if discovering
plagiarism
led you to walk away from Ellen White,
then if you're consistent,
you should also end up walking away from
what? Put it in the chat for me, please.
If you apply the same energy that you
apply to Ellen White,
oh, I found out that she's plagiarized.
I think she's plagiarizing. If I studied
to see and discover that she plagiarized
and here are the sources. If you apply
that same energy to the Bible,
if you walked away from Ellen White,
come on y'all.
If you walked away from Ellen White, the
next step, if you're consistent, is to
walk away from the Bible.
But in order to stay with the Bible, you
have to be inconsistent.
Yeah, you can't apply the same rules to
Ellen White that you do the Bible. Which
says to me, whoa, our critics
apply a higher standard to Ellen White
than they do the Bible. Isn't that
interesting?
Isn't that interesting?
Let's keep reading. Come on.
There's more. So, this is from the same
book. I'm going to skip it. You I think
you guys get the point. I'm going to
skip it. Uh, let's go to this one.
Wisdom literature. Proverbs versus the
instruction of Ammonop. Ammo. I think
that's how you pronounce it. The
teaching of Ammo and Proverbs 22
uh uh chapter 22:1 17 to chapter 24
verse 22. Further reflections on a
longstanding problem.
by JA Emerton Cambridge. Adolf man
argued in 1924 that Proverbs 22:17 to
Proverbs 24:10 is dependent on an
Egyptian sep uh sepatal
sepatal work the teaching of ammonop
ammo man these names. Since then, it has
been widely though never universally
agreed that this part of the book of
Proverbs or in the opinion of many, the
whole of those verses have been
influenced by this Egyptian source.
Whoa,
wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Proverbs.
Proverbs.
Oh, that was copy too. Now,
once again,
my point is not to say, oh, the Bible is
is therefore in error because of these
alleged alleged please note alleged
borrowings.
My argument is if you are keeping if you
are of the energy exercising the energy
that oh look this so-called prophet
copied from another source and therefore
they are not a prophet you must apply to
be consistent internally consistent you
must apply the same now listen y'all I'm
consistent I'm going to tell you I think
we as a church are consistent because I
can I can defend
the Bible being divinely inspired
in light of all of this and I will use
that same energy to also prove that
Ellen White is divinely inspired.
However, if you're applying the energy
that borrowing dismisses or borrowing
from someone else means you were not
inspired, then beloved, the only logical
conclusion is that you must walk away
from the Bible. I'm not encouraging you
to walk away from the Bible. I'm simply
saying the ex the the the energy you
used to dismiss Ellen White is a
dangerous energy because if you carry
that energy through to its logical
conclusion, you will walk away from the
Bible. But you don't carry it through to
its logical conclusion because you're
being partial.
You want to assume, well, everybody
knows the Bible's true. Really, the
skeptic doesn't assume that. And the
skeptic challenges you on that. The
skeptic says, "You're walking in blind
faith. You disregard all the evidence,
but you turn around and use that same
argument against Adventists."
Are y'all with me so far?
Keep that same energy.
Yeah. Let's keep going. Let's keep
going. So, here's the wisdom literature.
How about this? How about this? Let's
see.
All right, here we go. Biblical text.
For their lamp, for their command is a
lamp. Don't lust after her beauty. For
the prostitute will bring you to
poverty. Here's the Here's the ancient
text from Amino A&M. If you encounter a
moral woman, do not let her seduce you.
Her lips are sweet, but her feet are
evil.
The same energy that led you to walk
away from Ellen White should also lead
you to walk away from the Bible. I'm not
encourage encouraging you to walk away
from the Bible. I'm encouraging you to
check that energy that led you to walk
away from Ellen White. Let's keep
moving. Let's keep moving. So, here's
another one from the Atlantic Black
Star. There are many striking
similarities between the book of
Proverbs in the Bible and the Egyptian
instruction of A&M. And it goes on to
give even more examples. I'm going to
skip all those examples and let's go to
the next example. The next example in
this Atlantic Black Star article
and uh here it says here we go. Uh I'm
going to skip that too. Proverbs 23 and
Amino chapter 7. I'm not going to not
going to uh uh read all that. Let's keep
going.
Okay, here we go. In the Bible, the ten
commandments were given to Moses on
Mount Si and were written on tables of
stone supposedly by the hand of God
himself. Note that supposedly by the
hand of God himself. This is the
skeptic's argument. This is estimated to
have taken place around 1490 BC.
However, chapter 125 of the Egyptian
Book of the Dead around 2600 BC, which
would have been available to Moses
during his time in Egypt, seems to have
provided some inspiration. The Egyptian
book of the dead reads like the ten
commandments written in the negative
confession. Some examples are the book
of the dead, I have not blasphemed.
Exodus 20:7, thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. The
book of the dead, I have not defiled the
wife of a man. Uh, Exodus 2014, thou
shalt not commit adultery. The book of
the dead, I have not stolen. Exodus
2015, thou shalt not steal. You get the
picture.
The skeptic seizes upon this alleged
evidence and goes, "See, Moses
plagiarized." Now, watch this. The
Adventist skeptic
will go out on a limb. Come back for a
moment. Come back for a moment, y'all.
the Adventist skeptic, the the same
individual who will say, "Yeah, the
Adventists, they this and that, and I
don't like this and that." Will go out
on a limb to be like, "No, no, no.
Listen, you have to understand that in
the Bible, blah, blah, blah." Now, I it
doesn't even matter what they say. I
just want you to note the change of
energy.
Are you Are you seeing this? The change
of energy
They want the skeptic to No, no, no. You
got to understand the context and you
got to understand. No, no, no. It's not
really a no the No, let me explain. But
they don't give that same courtesy for
that which they do not want to be true.
Let's go back to the screen.
Psalm 104 and its parallel in the
Pharaoh Ahen Akhenitan's hymn. Themes
from the Egyptian great hymn of the
divine sundisk appear in Psalm 104.
Dangerous animals at night, human
activity during the day, a focus on
humans as opposed to Israelites, the
great power of water, and many more.
This is written by professor Aaron
Kohler
and
goes he goes on to say the American
Egyptologist Hen James Henry Breasted
who wrote his dissertation in Germany in
Germany and in Latin on Pharaoh
Aenathton drew attention more than a
century ago to the striking parallels
between the great hymn and Psalm 104. A
close comparison shows that there are a
large number of shared motifs in the
same order, including some motifs that
are not found anywhere else in the
Bible. Given that the hymn is earlier
than than Psalms, it would then be a
clear case of borrowing by one of the
biblical authors. All right, y'all.
KTSE
KTS.
the same energy,
the same inspiration
that led you to go, "Oh, Ellen White
borrowed, therefore, she's a false
prophet." Utilizing that same energy and
being consistent
will lead you to walk away from the
Bible,
which I believe is Satan's goal.
Now remember y'all, the purpose of my of
my study tonight is not to explain. I'm
not I'm not the purpose is not to
explain. No, no, no. The reason this is
wrong is because no, let the Adventist
critic do that.
And then as the Adventist critic
explains why the Bible, you know, no,
no, no, it's not this, then then ask the
Adventist critic to utilize that same
energy. Yes.
that same benefit of the doubt, that
same no, no, no, no, no. You know what?
I believe that this is truth and
therefore I'm going to do whatever I
need to do to defend it and I will never
I am just going to try to prove disprove
that the Bible is divinely inspired.
So we got one of two options.
If the Bible can be divinely inspired,
even if it borrowed from other sources,
h argument done.
If the Bible cannot be divinely inspired
and it bother borrowed from other
sources,
if you walked away from Ellen White, you
should walk away from the Bible. I'm
just saying keep that same energy. Wrong
energy will lead you to the wrong
conclusions. Right energy will keep you
safe. Right energy will lead you into
truth all the time. Right energy will
never lead you away from God.
Let's go back to the screen. Let's go
back to the screen, y'all. Uh law codes,
covenant code versus the code of ham ham
ham rabi.
If a man's ax hurts a ma a a man's
servant or maid, the owner must pay 30
shekels of silver.
Hammy rabbi is quote, "If an ox scores a
man's slave and kills him, his owner
shall weigh out 30 shekels of silver."
The same critic that wants you to have
mind blown when you see a sentence from
Ellen White that appears someplace else.
Ah, Lisa, wisdom can show up in multiple
places.
Wow,
that's a thought.
You mean God can can can speak to other
people?
Again, the purpose is not to explain
just how. I'm just trying to show you
the hippo
critic.
the the the the operation of the
hypocritic
of Ellen White.
Let's keep going and I'm going to start
skipping some of these Moses and the A&E
legal code. And then you'll see a bunch
of laws from Moses that parallel other
system in in in ancient Babylon, ancient
Mesopotamia. So, we're going to skip
this. We're just going to keep reading.
I just want you to see I got all this,
you know, when people like to stack up
the evidence and they say, "Look at all
these quotes from Ellen White and this
was borrowed from here and this was
borrowed from there." Do you do you take
that same energy into the Bible?
How about this one?
Judaism teaches pure monotheism while
Catholicism favors the trinity concept.
Yet, it is clearly a concept that was
influenced by other pagan religions
existing at the time that Christianity
came about. Examples of pagan trinities
are Ammon, Rah, uh, Ta of of the
Egyptian mythology, Anu, Enl, and A of
the Samrian mythology, and Ishtar, Baal,
and Tamuz of Babylonian mythology. H,
wait a minute. What?
The atheist
says that Christianity
got the whole idea of father, son, and
holy spirit from other sources. It was
borrowed. The 7th Day Adventist critic
just ignores that.
But he'll use the very same arguments
against Adventism.
He doesn't appreciate those arguments
that the atheist makes against the
Bible, but will use that very same
argument against Adventists.
Here's another one. Here's another one.
So, we're talking about plagiarism.
We're talking about borrowing. Here's
this one. Um um many gods besides Christ
have supposed have been supposed to die,
be resurrected and ascended to heaven.
The idea has now been traced back to its
original among primitive people in the
annual death and resurrection of crops
and plant life generally. According to
the advocates of the solar myth theory,
the ancient crucified saviors were
personifications of the sun and their
life story were allegorories of the
sun's passages through the 12
constellations of the zodiac. Let's keep
going. Uh y'all may remember a book or
may have heard about a book called the
the world's 16 crucified saviors. And in
this book, the world's 16 crucified
saviors or Christianity before Christ
contains new startling and extraordinary
revelations in religious history, which
discloses the oriental origin of all the
doctrines, principles, and precepts and
miracles of the Christian New Testament
and furnishing a key of unlocking many
of its sacred mysteries besides
comprising the history of the 16 heathen
crucified gods is an 1875 non-fiction
book written by American freethinker
Kirsty Graves, which asserts that Jesus
Jesus was not an actual person but was a
creation largely based on earlier
stories of deities or god men saviors
who had been crucified and descended to
and ascended from the underworld. Are
y'all catching this? Here are some of
those crucified saviors. Osiris, Horus,
Mithras,
at least some of them are saviors and
some said some of them are said to be
crucified saviors. Um, and
what we have in a nutshell
is what atheists would rejoice over.
Look at these
sources of plagiarism. Not to mention
Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John.
Not to mention Matthew, Mark, Luke, and
John. Throw those out, too. walk away
from Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John.
All right. So,
so the same anti-plagiarism energy that
leads you to reject Ellen White, if
consistently applied, will also lead you
to reject the Bible. Put a one in the
chat if you now understand and see why
keep that same energy when you have
negative energy is not a good thing
because now you're being a hypocrite.
Add Paul too. Yes.
Now you're being a hypocrite. Now the
atheist says, "Look at you. Look at you
silly Christians. Don't you know the
Bible is a bunch of plagiarized and
borrowed stories? You think it's
divinely inspired? You think that God
gave that? No, no, no. That came from
Babylon. That came from from the
Mesopotamia. That came from this story
and from that story. You y'all
understand what I'm saying? This is the
argument that that atheists use against
the Bible. And the Adventist skeptic or
the skeptic of Adventism, the critic of
Adventism, utilizes that same energy
towards Ellen White.
Keep that same energy.
Keep that same energy. Let's go to
energy number two. Energy number two.
And now y'all be begin to understand
where this is going. The hypocrites
argument. Five energies. Energy number
two is the energy of failed prophecy.
The energy of failed prophecies. Ellen
White's prophecies failed and therefore
she is a false prophet. Now again, I am
not even addressing whether Ellen
White's prophecies failed or not. That's
not the question.
Yes, Sonia, I'm saving that quote for
last.
I am saving that quote for last. And
yes, the core the energies I believe are
not from God because God is always
consistent.
As your do you as a critic, do you do
you have all the answers
to the Bible?
You know what they're going to say? No.
But yet you still trust it. Yeah.
But because you didn't have all the
answers for what you were looking at in
in in the writings of Ellen White,
you're like, "Oh, no." Now, remember the
critic says, "Oh, we place Ellen White
and the Bible on the same level." And
no, we don't.
But from this, we see, whoa, the critics
apply a higher standard to Ellen White
than they do the Bible. Because if they
apply the same standard to Ellen White
that they do the Bible, they would have
to walk away from the Bible, too.
They might say, "Oh, no, no, no, no. But
we've looked at the Bible and we've, you
know, we've uh we've answered these
these accusations against the Bible."
Why?
You didn't go in, you didn't go in
doubting, oh, wait a minute. Is the
Bible wrong? No, no, no. You were like
your your default position was we are
going to prove the Bible true. We are
going to prove the Bible right. So no
matter what I think it says, I know that
there must be an explanation. There must
be something that I'm just not
understanding. And once I get it, then
I'm going to be like, see, there's no
contradiction in the Bible, which we're
going to come to as well.
Because beloved, a lot of this boils
down to what you think inspiration is.
Did God dictate the words of the Bible?
Or were the were the prophets of the
Bible inspired in thought? Did God
dictate to them exactly what to write?
Or did God inspire them and then they
wrote in their own words? They wrote in
their own mentality. They wrote
according to their own personality.
There's a huge difference between verbal
the the theory of verbal inspiration.
Everything in the Bible that is written,
God directed. He was like dictating.
Okay,
write this exact word. And when I say
and write and
write the.
Every word in the Bible was dictated by
God. Is that what the Bible teaches? Or
did man did God use man and inspire man
and allow man to write out the truth in
his own words, in his own style?
In other words, freedom of choice. Oh,
come on. All right. Come on. Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go back. Failed
prophecies. Let's go. Let's go to the
screen. Ready? Keep that same energy.
Keep that same energy. Oh, the reason I
walked away from Ellen White is because
blah blah blah this. She said this and
this and that happened and she said
that. All right, keep that same energy.
Keep that same energy. Um, here's a book
100 false prophecies. False Bible
prophecies. 100 false Bible prophecies.
Now, now
my argument is not to say, "Oh, this
book is wrong." I'm not even addressing
that. I just want you to see what
skeptics of the Bible say.
Yeah.
Skeptics say 100 false Bible prophecies.
And you know what the critic of
Adventism will do here? They will say,
"No, no, no, no. You got to understand
the context. You got to understand
conditional prophecy." And you and all
and they will make every possible
argument to defend. But let's go. Let's
go. Let's just see some of these. Let's
see what some of the critics say here.
um some of the some of the critics of
the Bible. Okay, ready? Ezekiel
describes a future temple in detail. It
ne it was never constructed
historically.
Um here's another one. Nebuchadnezzar
would destroy Tyrant would be no more.
H Ty was besieged but survive. The city
still exists today. How about this one?
Egypt will be desolated for 40 years,
uninhabited. Outcome, there's no record
of a 40-year desolation. Here's another
one. These are, listen y'all, these are
arguments of the critics of the Bible.
This generation will not pass before all
these things happen. Jesus himself, what
if Ellen White said this? What if Ellen
White had said, "This generation will
not pass before all these." Do you know
how the critics would jump on? Ellen
White said, "Hold on, but when Jesus
says it, oh well, see, you got to
understand."
And what they do is they assume, well,
because you're a Christian, you're not
going to question Jesus. You're not
going to question the Bible, but you can
question Ellen White. But the critic of
the Bible says that's cultish. You're
not going to question the Bible because
you believe in a God. You believe in
God. So
the Bible could say anything and you
just believe in it because you choose to
believe. And the critic of the Bible,
the atheist says that's why Christianity
is a cult. And you know what the critic
of Adventism will do when he's in a
position like that? He will go on and on
about no, we're not a cult. And you got
to understand that when you look at the
prophecies, you got to and they will go
through. They take a default position
that they assume
they assume. Okay, here's my default
position. And it's my default position
because everybody else who believes the
same thing I do has the same default
position. But when challenged by the
atheist,
now all of a sudden,
you're going to you're going to you're
going to demand that the atheist has to
be reasonable and has to dialogue and
has to understand that there are
nuances, but you don't want to allow
that for the discussion with Ellen
White. No, no, no, no, no. You don't
want any, you don't want no Nope. But
you want that from the atheist, though.
Are y'all with me? put a one in the chat
if you're following my argument, if
you're understanding what I'm saying.
So, let's keep going. I'm gonna go to
the screen. I'm looking for the ones in
the chat. Paul's belief in Christ's
imminent return. We who are alive will
be caught up. Paul died long before
Christ returned. Um Jesus promised to
come quickly. Behold, I come quickly.
2,000 years have passed with no return.
How about this? Uh destruction of
Damascus prophecy. Damascus will become
a ruinous heap. Damascus has been
continuously inhabited. Here's another
one. David's line will rule forever.
How come? Literal monarchy ended. Some
interpret it messianically.
They're saying, in other words, it's not
really, but his monarchy ended. His line
ended. How about this?
Well, let me sum it up like this. The
same anti-f false prophecy energy that
leads you to reject Ellen White, if
consistently applied, will also lead you
to reject the Bible.
Jonah,
wait a minute, though. You know what
you're going to say? You know what the
Adventist, the critic of Adventism will
say? Well, you got to understand that
the prophecies and they'll begin to
explain and defend and put on their
apologetic hat, but they don't want to
put on the apologetic hat. And it's
unfortunate because so many Adventists
have walked away from Adventism based on
energies of atheism. Let me say it
again.
So many Adventists have walked away from
Adventism
based on the energies of atheism.
The same spirit atheism applies to the
Bible is the same spirit they apply to
the spirit of prophecy.
So if they applied that spirit
consistently,
in other words, if they weren't being
double-minded,
if they were being consistent, genuinely
consistent,
this the very reasons you walk away from
Ellen White should also lead you to walk
away from the Bible.
But yet you cling to the Bible.
You can't explain how all these
prophecies were not fulfilled. And you
know there are prophecies in the Old
Testament that were not fulfilled. You
can't explain it. But guess what? You
still believe in the Bible.
And you know what the atheist calls
that? The atheist calls that cultlike
behavior.
And you, Mr. Christian, you Mr. Seventh
Day Adventist critic, you Mr. the
Seventh Day Adventist is a cult because
they're not studying and they won't
don't want to see. You will look at the
atheists and deny, deny, deny. No, no,
no. You got to understand, you see,
you're just not being fair with the
Bible. You see, you're just not being
reasonable. Look, look, look. You know
what? It's because you're hard-hearted.
You don't want to hear evidence that
goes against what you believe. So, you
just you're just uh uh you know, you're
just being close-minded and you're just
trying to y'all y'all catch what I'm
saying.
All right, we're almost done. We're
almost there, y'all. We got three more
to go. So, hypocritic argument number
three, the anti-contradiction
energy.
So, what is this energy? Ellen White
contradicts herself and the Bible.
Therefore, she cannot be trusted.
Yeah.
You've heard people say that, right?
Adventist leaves.
Ads. Yes. Yes. Yes. I saw that. I caught
that.
So, the ad the the the the Oh, Ellen
White contradicts herself and she says
one thing here and another thing there
and you just don't know what to believe.
She contradicts herself all over the
place. And there's, you know, one
particular, no, I can't even say one
particular. Every YouTube Adventist
critic goes in on that. Oh, here she
says this, but she contradicts herself.
And there's so many contradictions in in
the Adventist system. Okay, keep that
same energy. Y'all put it in the chat
for me, please. KT,
keep that same energy. Let's go to the
screen. Let's go to the screen. Keeping
that same energy. What does that mean
for the Bible? Y'all ready?
Y'all may be familiar with that with
that list put out by several atheists,
several skeptics, 101 contradictions in
the Bible. Who incited David to count
the fighting men of Israel? 2 Samuel
24:1 God did. 1st Chronicles 21:1, Satan
did. In that count, how many men
fighting were men found in Israel? 2
Samuel 24:9, 8,000. 1st Chronicles 21:5,
1,100,000.
All right. How about this one? How many
fighting men were found in Judah?
500,000. 2 Samuel 24:9. 470,000.
1st Chronicles 21:5. God sent his
prophet to threaten David with how many
years of famine? 7, according to 2
Samuel 24:13. Three, according to 1st
Chronicles 21:12.
All right, let's keep going. Age
discrepancies in the Bible. How old was
Aariah when he began to rule over
Jerusalem? 22 according to 2 Kings 8:26.
42 according to 2 Chronicles 22:2. How
old was Jehoakin when he became king of
Jerusalem? 18 according to 2 Kings 24:8.
8 according to 2 Chronicles 36:9. Let's
keep going. Y'all listen. I told y'all.
I told y'all
this message is going to be hard for
everybody
if you're not studying the Bible.
If you're not deep down in the
scriptures, if you don't understand how
how inspiration works, you will struggle
just like the atheist and just like the
skeptic.
The purpose of this of this study is not
to lead you to doubt the Bible because
beloved, you have no reason to doubt the
Bible. The Bible is God's divinely
inspired word. Period. And there is
evidence for it.
incontrovertible evidence.
But if you're looking for evidence in
the wrong place, if you're looking for
hooks
to hang your doubt upon, you're going to
find them.
Come on, let's go back. Let's go back to
the timeline. Timeline discrepancies in
the Bible. How long did Jehoan rule over
Jerusalem? Three months. according to 2
Kings 24:8, three months and 10 days.
According to 2 Chronicles 36:9, the
chief of the mighty men of David lifted
lifted up his spear and killed how many
men at once? 800 according to 2 Samuel
23:8. 300 according to 1st Chronicles
11:1. Um, chronological discrepancies.
When did David bring the ark of the
covenant to Jerusalem? Before defeating
the Philistines or after? According to 2
Samuel 5 and6, after defeating the
Philistines? According to 1st Chronicles
13:14, before defeating the Philistines.
Let's keep moving, y'all. Faith versus
works. James chapter 2 verse 24, a
person is justified by works and not by
faith and and a person is justified by
works and not by faith alone. Ephesians
2:8:9, for by grace you have been saved
through faith, not works. Whoa, wait a
minute. Wait, what? What an obvious
contradiction, says the atheist.
But the critic of Adventism will say,
"No, no, no. Listen, you have to
understand, you got to you got to look
at it in cont.
They'll say context is king.
Context is king.
Here's why
James 2:24 doesn't contradict Ephesians
2 vers 8 and 9.
Absolutely, Marco. In other words, how
can the critics defend the word when
presented with the same arguments they
use against Ellen White?
It is hypocrisy.
Let's keep going. Law versus grace.
According to Romans 6:14, you are not
under the law, but under grace.
According to Matthew 5:17, I did not
come to abolish the law, but to fulfill
it. Let's keep moving. Law done away
with versus law remains. In Romans 3:31,
"Do we then make void the law through
faith? God forbid, ye, we establish the
law." Uh, Colossians 2:14, blotting out
the handwriting of ordinances that was
against us, which was contrary to us,
and took it out of the way, nailing it
to his cross. Um, Romans 7:12, for we
wherefore the law is holy, and the
commandment holy, and unjust and good.
Romans 6:14, for sin shall not have
dominion over you, for you are not under
the law, but under grace. What then
shall we sin because we're not under the
law, but under grace? God forbid y'all.
Do y'all see this?
The same spirit, that same keen eye to
say, "Here, Ellen White said this, but
here she said that." Why don't you apply
that same keen eye to the Bible?
Why is context king when it comes to the
Bible, but it is not king when it comes
to whatever else you read?
Let's go back to the screen. Eccles
Ecclesiastes 9:5, the dead know nothing.
Luke 16:23, in Hades, he was in torment.
Let's keep going. Jude 7, suffering the
vengeance of eternal fire. Malachi 4:1,
the day shall come and all shall be as
stubble.
Acts 16, believe in the Lord Jesus, you
shall be saved. Matthew 7:21, not
everyone who says, "Lord, Lord," will uh
will be saved, but he that doeth the
will of God.
Number of demoniacs healed. Matthew 28,
Matthew 8:28, two demon me two
demon-possessed men. Mark 5:2, a man
with an impure spirit.
Judah's death, Matthew 27 vers5, he went
and hanged himself. Acts chapter 1 vers8
he fell headlong his body burst open.
Genesis 6:19 two of every kind were to
be brought into the ark. Genesis 7:23
seven pairs of every unclean animal.
Jesus last words according to Luke 23:46
father into thy hand I commit my spirit.
According to John 19:30 it is finished.
According to Matthew 7 27:46 my God, my
God, why hast thou forsaken me? The same
critic that has a feast day, that has a
feast in trying to find how Ellen White
contradicts the Bible or how Ellen White
contradicts something she says someplace
else, literally has not much to say when
it comes to these.
Keep that same energy. Matthew 1,
Jesus's lineage traced through Solomon.
Luke 3, Jesus, Jesus's lineage traced
through Nathan.
The same anti-contradiction
energy that lead you to reject Ellen
White, if consistently applied, will
also lead you to reject the Bible.
Y'all put a one in the chat if you
follow me so far. Put a KTSC in the chat
if you're following me so so far. The
next time the critic says to you, Ellen
White plagiarized, you ask the critic,
"Hey,
what do you say about the uh atheists
who say that the Bible is plagiarized?"
And then just let them talk. Just let
them talk.
Just let them explain
why. We got to understand the the the
the surroundings and the watch how much
rope they how much leniency
they give
which is exactly what the atheists will
say is so cultlike. You Christians are a
cult.
Beloved, if you're using atheistic
principles and atheistic tactics
to disprove
what we believe as Adventists, you're on
the wrong ground.
There's an easy way to disprove what we
believe as Adventists.
There's an acronym for it. I call it B
A. We'll get to it in a moment.
You don't need to All of these arguments
that are used to lead lead people away
from the truth. are.
It It blows my mind
how we don't see that this is the very
thing atheists do with the Bible.
Come on, let's keep moving. We got two
more and then we're done. Two more and
then we're done. Argument number four,
energy number four, the
anti-controversial statements energy.
Ellen White said this. Ellen White said
that. Do you know what Ellen White said
about bicycles? Do you know what Ellen
White said about this? Or And we just
going like, look, can you believe? Can
you believe the audacity for her to say
this? All right. So, uh, Ellen White
made controversial statements.
Therefore, she cannot be a prophet of
God. I mean, come on. Look at how
ridiculous. This is obvious. Keep that
same energy. Exodus 21 20 and 21. When a
man strikes his slave.
Oh, Mr. Atheist, you've got to
understand, you see, in ancient Israel,
when the word slave was used, like you
got to understand the context and you
know what was happening at that time in
in ancient Israel. And and you know,
when you think about it, you you got to
understand that it wasn't like the the
slavery of of and and y'all let's come
back for a moment. Y'all do y'all y'all
know what I'm saying?
So we they just be No, no, no. You got
to understand that. I know, Mr. Atheist,
that this statement looks bad. I know it
looks like what a slave, but you got to
understand, which I absolutely agree.
You have to understand the context. I
agree there is nothing that let me not
say nothing. Most things that the skep
that that the Adventist critic would
argue towards the skeptic I can say yeah
you got to be consistent. You got to you
know that argument is is solid. However,
why not are why are you inconsistent
when it comes to something you don't
want to believe?
If you expect the atheist to be
fair-minded and hear out the details and
not come into this with a with a
stubborn stunt mind that no matter what
you say, I'm not going to believe it.
I'm going to defend my atheism till the
till the till the death. If you expect
the atheist to be honest and sincere in
heart and open-minded to see that look
when Jesus said this over here and he
said this over here or when Paul said
this here and then he said this there I
know it seems like a contradiction but
you got to understand yes just the
messenger the the the tone will change
you got to understand man you know yo
listen man we got to reason together
no not the same courtesy when it comes
to us saying, "Listen, listen. When
Ellen White said this here, if you take
what she says here and you bring them
together, then you get the context." No,
no, no, no, no. She contradicted
herself. I don't want to hear anything
else. And that's it. Done. La,
I can't hear you.
Let's go back to the screen. Let's go
back to the screen. When a man strikes
his slave with a rod, if the slave
survives a day or two, no vengeance
shall be taken. Uh you may acquire male
and female slaves from the nations, you
may be them to your sons after you to
inherit as a possession forever. Slaves,
obey your earthly master with fear and
trembling with a sincere heart as you
would with Christ. Do you know how much
of a field day atheists have with these
verses? The Bible is a is a is an
immoral book. And the critic
the critics the SDA the critics of
Adventism will sit there and say, "No,
you got to get Listen, let me explain.
Let me tell you why, Mr. Atheist. Let me
explain to you." It's almost like they
come to the Bible with a position of
innocent until proven guilty. And it
will never be proven guilty. Why?
Because I believe it. And if I believe
it, then it can never be proven guilty.
That's circular reasoning, you guys.
This is why this is why I love Adventism
because I didn't become a Christian just
because, well, there must be a God. No,
no, no, no, no. Something had to
convince me that the Bible was divine
inspired. Something had to convince me
that God was actually real and cared
about us. And that thing
is the very thing God said, "Here's how
I want you to test my word."
God didn't say
God didn't say, "I want you to test my
word by seeing if the number of years in
this historical account account written
by Moses matches the number of years
written by that historical account by
some." That's not how God said to test
my word.
That's not what God said. Here's how you
know. See, I'mma come to that. Let me I
I I
come Let me come back to that. Let me
keep moving. Let me keep moving. Come
on. Let's go back to the screen. Let's
go back to the screen. We're almost
there, y'all. A woman should learn in
quietness and full submission. I do not
permit a woman to teach or to assume
authority over a man. She must be quiet.
Be quiet in church. Women don't talk.
Women should remain silent in the
church. as they want to inquire about
something, they should ask their own
husbands at home. Whoa.
And you Christians think the Bible is a
divinely inspired book. This is what the
Bible says. And you know what the
critics who bla who seek to blast
Adventist because Ellen White said this
or Ellen White said that. Oh, you got to
understand you you got to understand
that that in that time what was
happening in the churches was and they
will go through and explain and go into
detail and show listen atheist if you're
reasonable then you will understand the
context. I know what it looks like on
the surface but you got to understand
the context. Why don't you allow that?
No. It's just like nope contradiction.
Oh wait, but there's context. No, no,
no, no, no. that what she said was
crazy.
Keep that same energy. Keep that same
energy. Numbers 31:17 and 18. Kill every
male among the little ones, but all the
young girls keep alive for yourself.
Deuteronomy 21:10-14, "When you see a
beautiful woman among captives and
desire, you may take her as your wife."
Can you imagine if Ellen White said any
of this?
Can you imagine how the how the a how
this advent skeptic would have that all
over the internet.
But you don't want to keep that same
energy when it comes to the Bible.
You're just like, "Oh, you know what?
Well, we're all Christians. So, as all
Christians, we're not going to look at
the hard parts of the Bible because we
already you don't have the answer for
it. I don't have the answer for it, but
you know, we're just going to wink our
eyes." No, no, no. Just like you didn't
want to wink your eyes being an
Adventist, I couldn't just close my eyes
to the discrepancies. Do the same thing
with the Bible.
Do the same thing. Be consistent.
KT S, but you will not Kts E because you
know if you KT E, you're going to walk
away from the Bible and you don't want
to walk away from the Bible. So, you
would rather just live in your mind with
the with the inconsistencies and the
contradictions, but you you couldn't do
that. You had to follow the Lord when it
came to Ellen White. You couldn't you
had to be genuine and honest. And I'm
not mocking. Please don't. But I'm just
I'm just trying to emphasize you had to
be genuine and honest with yourself. And
you had to you had to walk away. But if
you walked away because of those things
and you apply the same thing to the
Bible, walk away from it because the
same things exist in the Bible. Walk and
I'm not telling you, I don't want you to
walk away from it. I'm just saying the
energy that you applied in this case is
the wrong type of energy. And if you
consistently use that energy, it will
lead you to ultimately walk away from
the Bible.
And and interestingly enough,
Ellen White said something about that.
Isn't that crazy? We'll get to that in a
moment. Let's keep going. We're almost
done.
You shall not make any cuts or on your
body for the dead or tattoo yourselves.
I am the Lord. What? Tattoos? Really?
Really? The Bible said not to put
tattoos on yourself. Really?
That's what the atheist gonna say. This
is your book. This is your divinely
inspired book.
Come on. How about this one? It is
impossible for those who were once
enlightened and have tasted of the
heavenly gift and were made partakers of
the Holy Ghost and have tasted the good
word of God and the powers of the world
to come if they shall fall away to renew
them again unto repentance, seeing they
crucify to themselves the son of God and
put him to an open shame. You mean to
tell me that if a person sins after they
become a Christian that they have fallen
away and they cannot repent anymore?
If if Ellen White wrote that in her own
words, the critics would be all over it.
But you know what they did when they
come to Hebrews 6 vers 4-6? Well, you
know, you got to understand the context.
And I agree, there is a context.
There is a context.
You got to understand the context to
understand what the text is saying.
I know some of you e even among
Adventists right now, some of you like,
I've never seen some of this stuff
before. Beloved, listen to me. None but
those who have fortified their minds,
let's come back for a moment to the
screen. None but those who have
fortified their minds with the truths of
God's word will stand through the last
great crisis.
When the atheist attacks your faith,
your belief, beloved, you have to know
why you believe what you when they
present all these all these the same
people that walked away from Adventism
when presented with this stuff. Guess
what? You going to walk away from the
Bible. Well, I saw that the I didn't
know that Ellen White wrote Desire of
Ages and that sentence came from that
author. If she's a prophet, then how
could she? But guess what, y'all? That's
a that's the that's such the wrong
approach to arriving at truth because if
you do that with Ellen White, if that
was able to get you to leave,
what do you think is going to happen
when the atheist pushes on you?
Look at these verses.
Look at this plagiarism. Look at these
contradictions in the Bible.
Look at these tough sayings in the
Bible. Look at these false prophecies in
the Bible. It will be hypocritical of
you to remain a Christian while you
walked away from Adventism for the very
same reasons.
Let's go back to the screen. The same
anti-controversial
statements energy that led you to reject
Ellen White, if consistently applied,
will also lead you to reject the Bible.
You sure you want to keep that same
energy?
Are you sure you want to keep that same
All right, so we're gonna go to that
last one. Last energy must warn against
false prophets energy. Ellen White is a
false prophet and it is our duty to make
YouTube video after YouTube video after
YouTube video to warn against false
prophets. But here's a problem with
that. Keep that same energy. Keep that
same energy. It's interesting how you
got all these prophets today. Kim
Clement, Lance Wallnau, Dutch Seats,
Chuck Pierce. I'm not going to name just
Just think about all the other modernday
prophets today.
Where are your videos about these
people?
Where are your
warnings
against all these people? Have you
searched them? Have you checked them
out?
Why? Why the attention on just Ellen
White?
Why all the attention? Is there only one
prophet, one quote unquote false prophet
that you know of that you got to divert
your whole ministry and your whole life
and your whole livelihood and
everything?
You know how many quote unquote
so-called prophets are walking around
right now? Where the where are the
warnings? Where are the warnings?
If you kept that same energy because
here's a false prophet, therefore we
must make videos about about this false
prophet. What about all the or is it is
it just none of these are false
prophets? Everybody is cool except Ellen
White. That begins to make me feel a
little bit suspicious.
A little bit suspicious. H Ellen White
is the only false prophet. You know,
you think she's a false prophet and
that's it. And all of all the prophets
today, the whole NRA movement with all
these thousands of false prophets on
YouTube and all over and and all we see
all your whole anger, your whole
ministry is just dedicated to one of
these so-called false prophets. Where is
the concern for all the other people
who are following these people? Have you
researched their sermons?
Maybe your concern isn't really about
false prophets, is it?
Maybe there's just a need to vindicate
why you left and
make yourself feel
like you did the right thing.
So, you just got to keep coming back and
coming back and coming back and like,
"Okay, here's why."
instead of maybe going out and all
right, I'm gonna go evangelize to to the
rest of the world and just talk about
Jesus since that's what I, you know,
that's what we didn't do in Adventism.
So, I'm just going to talk about Jesus.
No, I'm going to
I got to focus on that one prophet.
Forget about all the other prophets. I'm
not even going to research them. I mean,
you know why? It's not going to get it's
not going to get views.
Let's go back to the screen.
Where are the videos? Where are the
videos about all the prophets?
Prophets talking about angels, angels in
Africa, the African angels,
the Mexican angels. Where are
Where are all the videos about
other prophets?
Keep that same energy.
So
the same must warn against false
prophets energy that leads you to reject
Ellen White if consistently applied
would also lead you to focus on others
who claim to have the prophetic gift.
But we don't see that, do we? We don't
see that.
And that's a strange thing.
That's a strange thing. Yeah. Where are
the critics when these other prophets
prophesy what's going to happen and how
the Israel and where are where where are
the critics then?
So, let's go back to the screen as we as
we begin to wrap this up. We've covered
the five energies and we've seen that
keeping that same energy is really not a
good thing to do because that same
energy will lead you to walk away from
the Bible. And that fifth energy is just
showing your inconsistency.
Listen, how do we apply consistent
standards? If we dismiss Ellen White for
using outside sources, we should also
apply the same standard to biblical
writers who drew from ancient texts. If
we if we if Ellen White's unfulfilled
prophecies discredit her, we must judge
biblical prophets with with conditional
predictions by the same measure. If we
appar if apparent contradictions in
Ellen White's writings undermine her
authority, similar tensions in the Bible
should raise equal concerns.
If we dismiss based upon hard
statements, we should then dismiss the
Bible. If we have a burden to warn
against false prophets, then that burden
should be universal and not singular.
Honest scholarship, honesty requires
consistency. The same context and
understanding we give to scripture, we
should extend to all claimed prophetic
writings.
So what are the double standards? You'll
condemn Ellen White for using external
sources, but wink and I if the Bible
does it. No, I didn't even say when the
Bible does it. I just said if the Bible
does it. You'll try to find a reason
why. No, no, no. It's not borrowed. Oh,
but you will do your best to defend to
give the the the Bible the benefit of
the doubt. And you think, oh, well,
that's a Christian thing to do. But no,
no, no, no. The atheist doesn't think
that. The atheist thinks you're being
blind. The atheist thinks you're being
cultic. You're being brainwashed by your
leaders, by your pastors.
You reject Ellen White for apparent
failed prophecies, yet trust the Bible
despite alleged fail prophecies. You
discredit Ellen White for alleged
alleged contradictions in her writings,
yet you wink an eye when it comes to the
Bible. Uh, you mock Ellen White for hard
statements, yet you try to explain away
the hard statements of the Bible. You
criticize Ellen White all over the place
and are silent
when it comes to to to all the other
so-called prophets that are alive today.
the inconsistency, the the hippocritics
of YouTube.
This is the hypocrisy.
And it is stunning. It is mindblowing.
So the question is, how then should we
test a prophet? I'm not saying don't
test a prophet. I'm just saying how then
should we test a prophet.
Yeah. And it's simple, y'all. It's
simple.
To the law and to the testimony. If they
speak not according to this word, it is
because there is no light in them.
That's how we test a prophet. We don't
test a prophet by whether they borrowed.
We don't test a prophet by did she did
the prophet say something hard. We don't
test a prophet by does it look like
there's a contra. We test a prophet by
this. Do they speak according to the law
and the testimony?
That is it.
That's how you test a prophet.
What are they teaching?
Yes, their lifestyle obviously.
Are they living? Watch this. Are they
living according to the law and to the
testimony?
But yet you want to say there's no law.
You want to say there's no law.
So, how can you test a prophet if you
don't even obey the law?
How can you test a prophet if you're not
even in the place to test a prophet?
You're not even li You're You're not
even
How can you test a prophet
with something that you do not believe
doesn't exist? You do not believe
exists.
Here's the weirdest thing to me. of all
the prophets today, right?
The Bible says in 1 Corinthians 4:32,
"The spirits of the prophets are subject
to the prophets." Y'all want to know
what that means? It's very simple.
Any prophet that came after Moses had to
be in line with Moses. Any prophet that
came after a prophet that came after
Moses had to be in line with that
prophet and with Moses. So every prophet
that comes on the scene later and later
and later has a greater burden to be in
line with all the prophets before them.
Why? Because the spirit of the prophets
are subject to the prophets. A future
prophet cannot override or cannot uh uh
cannot uh contradict a former prophet.
So so so Jeremiah would have been
subject to Moses.
Daniel would have been subject to Moses.
John the revelator would have been
subject to Daniel and Jeremiah and
Moses.
The spirit is not going to contradict
itself.
So then if every prophet had a greater
burden of falling in line with all the
prophets that came before them, then
it's very simple. If a modern-day
prophet arises, we just got to ask a
question. Do they fall in line with all
the prophets before them? And how would
we know that?
To the law and to the testimony. That's
how you know that. That's how we know if
a prophet is really a prophet. Because
the prophet is going to speak on is
going to to be in line with previous
revelation. So what does that mean? What
does that mean for us today? Here's what
it means.
Any prophet,
any so-called prophet
that does not understand the work of the
last prophet is not a prophet.
Done deal.
If the last biblical prophet was John
the Revelator, then any prophet that
comes after him must be in line with
what John the Revelator said. And if a
prophet, it amazes me how many of these
modern-day prophets will be like, "Oh,
God's given me a word for you. God's
given me a word for you." "Yeah, I'm a
prophet." And I'll be like, "Can you
explain the book of Revelation to me?"
Well, hold on. What? Well,
well,
how are you a prophet and you don't
understand Revelation?
How are you a prophet and you don't
understand the work of the last prophet?
And in order order to understand the
work of the last prophet John the
revelator, you must also understand the
work of the prophet Daniel. Which means
then that any modernday prophet that
does not understand the teachings of
Daniel and Revelation is not a modernday
prophet.
So now take your Joseph Smith, take your
modern day prophets, take any prophet
you want and take Ellen White. And how
are we going to test whether these are
prophets or not? Well, let's just see.
How do they line up with Daniel and
Revelation?
Who can explain?
Yeah. Okay. Visions. All right. We're
told that there's going to be false
visions. Uh uh miracles. All right.
We're going to we're told they're going
to be false miracles. So, let's not even
look at at Ellen White holding up a
Bible above her head. Let's not look at
her not breathing because for all we
know, that might be satanic. Satan has
the power to do miracles. But one thing
Satan cannot do is tell the truth.
So let's take Ellen White and then let's
take all these modern day prophets and
let's take Joseph Smith and let's take
this prophet here and that prophet here
and let's look at their let's not look
at oh did they contradict themselves?
Oh, did they borrow? No, no, no, no.
That that's all garbage, y'all. Those
are all atheistic methods of trying to
disprove the Bible. Why would we use
atheistic methods to apply to the Bible
and for that matter to apply to Ellen
White? Oh, look, there's a
contradiction. Oh, look, it's a hard
saying. No, no, no. The atheist mind
does not understand how the word of God
operates. And unfortunately, many
Christian minds do not understand how
the word of God operates. So, let's talk
about that for a second before we wrap
this up. Come on.
So there are two views of inspiration in
the Bible. There is thought inspiration
where God inspires the thoughts rather
than dictating exact words allowing for
human expression and cultural context.
And then there is verbal inspiration
where where those who believe verbal
inspiration believe that God dictated
the exact words of scripture to the
writers. Every word is directly inspired
and selected by God. Now watch this.
Come back for a moment.
This is why.
See, for the Muslim, listen to me y'all.
For the Muslim, the Quran is the word of
God because in their minds, God dictated
the exact words to Muhammad.
So they believe in verbal inspiration.
The reason they believe the Bible cannot
be inspired is because look at all the
translations. How can you translate the
word of God? If God gave the Bible then
it how these translations are are
changing the words and if the words are
changed then how can it be the word of
God? And unfortunately beloved most
Christians take that view. And so you
will see Christians trying to defend. I
know it says in this verse that there
were two demoniacs and in that verse
there was one demoniac. But then they
have to they have to for themselves
prove that that oh well here's why it's
not because they're they believe that
the word that the exact words on the
page two versus one must be divinely
inspired.
Are y'all catching this
beloved? We do not believe that God in
if God wanted to dictate the words. He
He wrote the Ten Commandments himself.
God could have written the Bible
himself, but he didn't. He spoke through
individuals who had freedom of choice
and they chose their own words to
express the thought. It's the thought
that was inspired, not the exact word
Moses wrote. So the word and and the
word is, those words aren't inspired.
Humans wrote the Bible and humans are
imperfect. And that's why you will find
imperfections in the Bible. But that
does not make the word of God less
divine because beloved the the divinity
is not in the words. The divinity is in
the concepts given in the Bible.
So when I explain to you the love of God
from my own perspective because I said
it in words different from the next
person doesn't mean that it is less
inspired. the concept of of Jesus dying
for our sins and the lamb slain from the
foundation of the world and God sending
down his son. It is the concept that
that God is is giving to humanity.
And when you understand that the Bible
is thought inspired,
when you see one author say this and
another author say that and they're
writing from their different
perspectives. Now you're not you okay a
author borrowed from someone else. It's
the thought that's inspired. In fact,
let me say it this way.
When
you take
someone else's sentence,
someone else's thought on a particular
thing and if you just copy that entire
thought, put it, let me say it this way.
The critics love to say that Ellen White
plagiarized. If she plagiarized, I would
ask this question. Show me one other
author
that has the great controversy theme in
their writings.
If all her ideas are borrowed, show me,
watch this, y'all. Show me what other If
her ideas were borrowed,
then she would be reflecting the very
principles, the very thoughts that these
other authors reflect. But guess what?
You can't find it anywhere, can you?
How are the critics on one hand going to
be like, you know what, these teachings
are so unorthodox, but yet, oh, but she
plagiarized. Really?
Oh, you mean she took an idea from here
and and put it in her own context in a
totally different paradigm?
How you going to accuse somebody of
plagiarizing and then say, "Oh, but
their ideas don't match up with the
person that they plagiarized."
Seriously.
Like for all this talk of plagiarism,
you would surely think that you could
find the entire great controversy theme
in some other book, some other place.
But no, they accuse Adventists of being
so unorthodox in the things that we
believe and how we believe it and how we
look at the Bible. Huh? How do those two
things go together? Help me to
understand.
You see beloved once you come from a
place where you are are trying to prove
something wrong it doesn't matter what
anybody says after that you're on a
track you got an energy now and the
energy is prove this wrong at all costs.
So when we understand
that it is thought inspiration and not
verbal inspiration, then we're not going
through reasons of trying to defend why
one said one demon and the other said
two. It's not that important.
It has nothing to do
with the theme of salvation that God has
placed in the Bible. God's truth cannot
be altered. But you could tr you could
translate the Bible in different words
and some people translate it better than
others.
Some translations are good and some
translations are not good. And yet the
critics will read all those Bibles. Be
like, "Oh, well, you know, this
translation is a little bit better than
this one." You know what that says? If
the words themselves were inspired, it
would be a sin to translate the Bible
because now you're messing with the
words of God.
Are y'all understanding what I'm saying?
Inspired writers remain human with
limitations in knowledge and expression
that don't negate the divine origin or
core of their message. Ellen White was
human.
Paul was human.
Moses was human. Jeremiah human. David
human.
Imperfect people wrote the Bible.
And if imperfect people wrote the Bible,
we may expect to find
imperfections in the Bible.
That does not mean that there are
imperfections in God's truth because
God's truth is unassailable.
The Bible teaches that when the dead
die, they nothing. They know nothing.
The Bible teaches that there will be a
judgment before Jesus comes again. The
Bible. So if you want to test whether
whether someone is teaching the truth or
not, you don't look for contradictions
or oh they got this historical fact
wrong by a day or by a month or no no no
no. You ask a simple question. Are they
teaching according to the Bible?
Bible all day.
And so our critics love to try to try to
say, "Oh, look at Ellen." They want you
to focus on Ellen White
because when it comes to a straight up
Bible only discussion,
well, well, no matter what you say,
well, you're just getting that from
Ellen, but I'm just showing you Bible.
No, well, you're getting that from Ellen
White's interpretation of the Bible.
See, and it just it's like, wow. It's
almost like you're talking to an
atheist.
Okay, I got three more slides. You can
probably see it on the screen. Four more
slides. Check this out, y'all. Very
interesting statement. While God has
given ample evidence for faith, he will
never remove all excuse for unbelief.
All who look for hooks to hang their
doubts upon will find them. And those
who refuse to accept and obey God's word
until every objection has been removed
and there is no longer an opportunity
for doubt will never come to the light.
Courtesy,
Ellen White.
If you're looking for doubts, you'll
find them.
So the same way you were looking for
doubts without a white, go ahead and
apply that same principle to the Bible.
And guess what? You're going to begin to
see, oh, wait a minute. Atheists and
skeptics are saying that this story was
barred from this. And there are 16
crucified saviors before Jesus was even
born. And and the trinity was was pagan
and and and the Genesis story. And and
beloved, guess what? And guess what?
What's going to happen is
if you're consistent with that same
energy, you're gonna walk away from the
Bible.
There was a statement I always read that
I was like, "Well, why would she say
that?" And now I get it. Here it is. It
is Satan's plan to weaken the faith of
God's people in the testimonies. Satan
knows how to make his attack. He works
upon minds to excite jealousy and
dissatisfaction towards those at the
head of the work.
Interesting, huh?
It's always Wow. Oh my Lord have mercy.
He works upon minds to excite jealousy
and dis dissatisfaction towards those
who are at the head of the work. Be
careful, y'all.
Be careful
of how
you speak about those at the head of the
work.
The gifts are next questioned. Then of
course they have but little weight and
instruction given through vision is
disregarded. Watch this y'all. Next
follows skepticism in regard to the
vital points of our faith, the pillars
of our position, then doubt as to the
holy scriptures, and then the downward
march to predition. Do y'all see this?
She literally says,
"If you doubt the testimonies,
you're going to end up
walking away from the Bible itself." And
I would wonder why would she say that?
And
it's not because the testimonies are
more important than the Bible. That's
not what she was saying.
What you're saying is
it is the doubt.
It is the doubt.
The doubt in truths proven by the word
of God. When you begin to get that seed
planted in your mind and you apply that
to the testimonies, which we believe are
divinely inspired,
not Ellen White's words verbatim, but
the thoughts God gave to her were
inspired. She knew how to take thoughts
from other sources and package them into
a unique
picture, a unique paradigm that no one
else has.
But when you doubt,
and why do you doubt? Oh,
I saw I noticed copying here.
Oh, I noticed uh what looks like a
contradiction here. Oh. Oh, this must be
a false prophecy. Oh, oh, uh, uh, here's
a hard saying. That same spirit,
if you are being consistent, is going to
lead you out of Christianity altogether.
And the reason why people are aren't
leaving Christianity is because they're
not being consistent. They are being
hypocritical. So, which is better? Which
is better?
Walking out or being hypocritical and
staying in?
So you guys,
um,
let me just read these off and then
we're going to close out in prayer. The
higher standard dilemma. Critics
apparently hold Ellen White to a higher
standard than they do the Bible. A isn't
that something else?
The critics of Adventism apply apply a
higher standard to themselves person for
themselves personally. They apply a
higher standard. They hold Ellen White
to a higher standard than they do the
Bible. And yet they claim that we are
the ones that hold Ellen White to a
higher standard than we do the Bible.
The same critical method that would
discredit Ellen White would equally
undermine biblical authority if applied
consistently.
Critics often accept explanations for
biblical difficulties that they reject
when applied to Ellen White's writings.
Demanding perfect originality, literal
fulfillment, and absolute consistency
from Ellen White while allowing
flexibility in biblical interpretation
reveals a problematic bias. Are y'all
with me?
So, what are the principles for
consistent evaluation? One, consider
historical, cultural, and literary
context for both biblical and modern
prophetic writings. Focus on the
spiritual purpose and message rather
than demanding technical perfection.
Interpret difficult passages in the
light of the writer's entire body of
work, not in isolation.
Approach apparent contradictions with a
willingness to seek harmonization rather
than immediately rather than immediate
dismissal.
Ain't that fair?
Conclusion, y'all.
You want to be able to keep that same
energy.
Negative energy will lead to error
disguised as truth. Positive energy will
lead to truth.
Positive energy demands consistent
standards of evaluation for all claimed
prophetic writings, the Quran, the
Bible, everything.
Be consistent. Be consistent. Recognize
the human element in divine
communication while affirming the
inspired message. Focus on the fruits
and purpose of prophetic ministry rather
than isolated criticisms. and neither
uncritical uncritically ex neither
uncritically accepts all claims nor
dismisses genuine prophetic guidance.
It's that simple, y'all.
It's that simple. They are literally
doing the same thing they accuse
Adventists of doing.
They are exalting Ellen White,
applying a higher standard to her than
they do the Bible.
So listen y'all.
Let I'm concluding with this thought.
Let's come back come back to the screen.
Concluding with this thought you you
guys. I keep the same energy.
I have the the same energy when it comes
to the Bible. I got that same energy
when I'm reading Ellen White. And I
don't change energies. I don't have to
change energies. I got that same if I'm
investigating the Quran. I got the same
energy. I have the same energy.
I'm consistent.
And because when I approach the Bible,
I'm looking at context. I'm looking at
yeah, that others will think this is a
contradiction, but in actuality, if you
look at the context, you're going to see
that it's not a contradiction. and and
and and and places where where where
this factor is off or that factor is
off. That does not affect the big
picture of the Bible because the Bible
is not verbally inspired. It is thought
inspired. Men of God spake as they were
moved by the Holy Ghost. They were moved
by the Holy Ghost. The men were inspired
and they wrote to express their thoughts
in their own words. So, as I look at the
Bible and and I and I and I see
comparisons between other sources
outside the Bible, oh, there's a Genesis
story there. Why are there Genesis
stories all over? Oh, maybe because
Genesis actually happened.
Maybe
there are so many Genesis stories
from different sources.
Maybe that might be an evidence. How are
How are all these people saying the same
thing?
So, as I'm looking at the Bible, and I
don't believe the Bible is is is divine
because I have to believe it. I believe
the Bible is divine because I have
studied it out.
And so these when these atheists throw
these things, oh, what about this that
that
listen y'all? Can we focus on what makes
the Bible divine? Let me show you
something. Come with me to the book of
Daniel and let me have you explain this.
Come with me to the book of Revelation
and let me show you what's happening in
America right now and you tell me of
another book on the planet that does
what the Bible does.
I have no these things don't phase me.
And so when I take that same energy and
put it towards the writings of Ellen
White, oh what she says matches exactly
with Daniel and Revelation. And beloved,
let me tell you something. If you don't
understand Daniel and Revelation, how
can you even open your mouth to critique
If you don't even understand Daniel and
Revelation for yourself, how can you
open your mouth to critique the prophet?
If they're speaking on Revelation, if if
if we're testing them by what the last
prophet said, how can you even open your
mouth if you don't understand what the
book says?
And so, you know what God is saying in
all that? Study the Bible for yourself.
And when you study the Bible and when
you understand the truth of the Bible,
you will then be able to determine false
prophet versus true prophet. But you
have no business, oh that's a false
prophet, when you can't even break down
the book. You don't even understand what
the last prophet says. How are you going
to judge what this person is saying when
you don't understand the last prophet
for yourself?
Okay.
How does a skeptic respond to this
challenge? Not by telling me, "Oh, well,
Ellen White, no, no, no, no, no. I
already know everything you say about
Ellen White. I don't need to hear more.
I already know what the atheists and the
skeptics says about the Bible. I don't
need to hear more. I know their
arguments and I know your arguments.
What I'm saying to you, Seventh Day
skeptic, skeptic, critic of the Seventh
Day Adventist Church, critic of Ellen
White, is keep the same energy. That's
all. And if you think that keeping the
same energy will be safe for you when it
comes to the Bible, you're in serious
trouble.
Because whatever energy you put into
trying to prove that the Bible is still
the word of God, you should have put
that same energy
into any other work that claimed that
it's the word of God, not the word of
God that claimed that it is divinely
inspired by God. Please excuse, excuse
me, that claim that it is divinely
inspired by God.
If it's a Quran and someone's saying,
"Hey, the Quran is a word of God." Okay,
let's test it. I'm not going to go to
the Quran be like, "No, it's not." No,
let's test it. Cuz if I walk away saying
the Quran is not the word of God, I'll
be able to tell you why. Not because,
"Oh, it's a contradiction here or
there." I'm not judging on that. I'm not
judging on, "Oh, was there a mistake
here?" The Muslims might judge it like
that. I'm not judging it like that.
Because if I judge their book like that,
I got to judge my book like that. Be
consistent.
keep that same energy.
All right,
that's it y'all. That's a wrap.
Uh I hope this message today
forgot to drink my water.
I hope uh I hope for those of you who
have been struggling
how do I answer the critics struggling
you know maybe struggling with Ellite I
hope that tonight's message
tonight's study
has opened your eyes
to understand things a little bit better
so y'all put a one in the chat I just
want to see put a one in the chat you
know the higher the number, the the the
the better you receive this. So, if you
put a 10 in the chat, I'm going be like,
"Okay, yeah, y'all got this." You put a
nine, you put a eight, don't I hope
nobody puts a one. But listen,
we have not believed cunningly devised
fables.
And if a if if a thousand people leave
the church today, please y'all do not
truth is never in numbers.
Truth is never in numbers. You need to
think. You need to ask God for wisdom.
And do not let the devil outsmart you.
Cuz that's what he's trying to do. The
devil was wroth with the woman and went
to make war with the remn of her seed.
He's not making war with any of these
other billions of prophets walking
around saying, "God showed me. God gave
me a word for you." No war with them.
But there sure seems to be
a calculated and concentrated assault.
Why?
Why? Ask yourself that question. Why?
Heavenly Father, thank you for tonight.
Thank you for your word. Thank you,
Lord, for showing us that our truths
stand on the Bible.
Thank you for showing us, Lord, that
that the same spirit that the skeptics
use towards Ellen White is what atheists
use towards the Bible. Literally, it is
the exact spirit.
Lord, speak and let these people know
they do not know what manner of spirit
they are of.
Open their eyes. Open their hearts.
And Lord, help us to be wiser than the
enemy's plots, wiser than the enemy's
attacks upon
your church.
Please Lord,
solidify us in the truth.
Solidify us on your word is our prayer
in Jesus name. And I pray for any who
who have walked away, maybe watching
this presentation, have walked away. I
pray Lord that you would bring them back
into the fold, whether they are known or
unknown. Lord, help them to see they
they left based on a lie. They left
based on things that would cause them to
leave the Bible itself if they're
consistent.
Please Lord, open their eyes. Bring them
back into the truth is my prayer in
Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Thank you everyone. Um
good study tonight. I agree. And may God
bless you and keep you as you continue
uh to study his word and to walk in
truth. Amen.